Weslley Victor da Costa Vieira

Porto, Portugal +351 912 018 056 w3slley.victor@gmail.com

w3slley.github.io



ABOUT ME

I utilize technologies such as JavaScript, Node.js, PHP and MySQL to build and deploy full-stack web applications, having previous experience with Digital Ocean's VPS and the Heroku cloud platform. Given my background in a STEM field, I also have experience with data analysis using tools such as Python and SQL. I'm passionate about learning and I have a special interest in back-end web development and DevOps.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming languages: C/C++ (familiar), Java, JavaScript, TypeScript, Python, PHP

Front-end development: HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap4, jQuery

Back-end development: Node.js, Express, Laravel Databases: MySQL, MongoDB (familiar)

Data analysis: pandas, numpy, matplotlib, SQL

LANGUAGES

Portuguese (Native) **English** (Fluent) German (Beginner) Spanish (Beginner)

Version Control: Git, GitHub, GitLab

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Software Developer at Kompetenza

May 2021 – Present

- √ Implementation of RESTful APIs using Node.js/Express (deployed on Heroku) and integration with Salesforce's platform
- . \checkmark Used JavaScript, Apex, Flow Builder, Process Builder, Lightning Experience, among others

Full-Stack Developer at Accio

Mar 2021 - Present

- ✓ Part of the development team responsible for the implementation of new features on the product ✓ Implemented the MVC software design pattern on back-end code and DevOps practices on deployment process
- ✓ Used PHP, MySQL, JavaScript, ¡Query and Semantic UI

Research Assistant at CAUP

Feb 2020 - Dec 2020

- ✓ Implemented a Python software using statistical tools such as Markov chain Monte Carlo to improve measurement of uncertainties on velocities of stars with the goal of setting constrains on dark matter present on ultra-faint dwarf
- 🗸 Utilized the following Python libraries: numpy, pandas, matplotlib and astropy, among others

PERSONAL PROJECTS

Personal blog

GitHub | Website

- ✓ Developed a personal blog and deployed it on the Heroku cloud platform
- ✓ Utilized Node.js and Express in the back-end, and MySQL as the database

Origami

GitHub | Website

- ✓ Developed a web application that allows users to write and store personal notes online
- Used PHP as the server side language and MySQL as the database. Ajax (implemented with jQuery) was also used

Wikipedia Covid-19 Charts Generator

GitHub

✓ Developed a Python script that parses the DGS website for daily Covid-19 reports and generates timeline charts and summary tables with the goal of contributing to Portugal's Wikipedia page

Endenda Mais

GitHub | Website

- ✓ Implemented website the for science communication project called Entenda Mais
- The project was developed using the PHP framework Laravel and MySQL

EDUCATION

Universidade do Porto

September 2018 – September 2021 (expected)

Major: Bachelor's Degree in Physics

Minor: Computer Science

CS Coursework: Data Structures and Algorithms, Algorithm Design and Analysis, Web Technologies, Computer Networking, Databases, Functional Programming